Ramesh Ojha

Having 6+ years of experience in programming (mostly in front-end), and I am looking for a good opportunity where I can enhance my core skills. I also have an engineering degree and have good knowledge of computer science and information technologies. Currently pursuing master's course from online distance education.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Coforge Limited

Dec 2023 - Present

- Worked on complicated screens development with approximately 10-15 API calls on single page.
- Did R&D, POC and implementation of Dark Mode from scratch.
- Followed test driven development approach for repo migration.
- Worked on technologies like NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Axios, MUI, Storybook, Jest (RTL), HTML, SCSS, GIT and AWS.

Solution Engineer, Degode

Jun 2021 - Dec 2023

- Did R&D, POC and implementation of whitelabeling in the legacy project based on automated chat-support application.
- Debugged production level bugs and resolved it in quick time.
- Created atomic and molecular components for UI in ReactJS.
- Have implemented servers and connected it to database.
- Worked on TypeScript, NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, ExpressJS, MongoDB, GrapghQL, Socket.io, GIT, Jenkins and AWS.

Junior Developer, Arikaptics

Nov 2018 - Apr 2021

- Contributed in development of e-commerce application supporting accounting.
- Wrote CRUD operations queries for database.
- Implemented auth using JWT menthod.
- Technologies used ReactJS, TypeScript, Redux, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, TypeORM, Axios, REST and GIT.

Educational Background

Master of Computer Application (MCA) (Pursuing Currently)

Indra Gandhi National Open University Jan 2023 - Present

· Learning DSA, ML, AI, Python and System Design.

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering

Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

• Got exposure to C, C++, HTML and CSS.

Contact

Noida Sector 59 +91-9540205885 ramstartwork@gmail.com www.rameshojha.com leetcode - rameshojha3131

Skills

Frontend Skills

- NextJS, ReactJS, Redux
- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- JavaScript, TypeScript

Backend Skills

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB, TypeORM
- Python

Additional Skills

- · AWS, Jenkins, Vercel, ArgoCD
- Jest, RTL, Enzyme
- · Python, Docker

Certification/Short Courses

- · Responsive Web Designing
- Javascript Algorithm & Data Structure
- Frontend Development Libraries
- NextJs
- Advanced React & Storybook

Additional Information

- Managing 2-3 Junior Developers in my current project.
- Participate in extra curricular activites and campus sports competition.